Patrick Bower

www.patrickbower.com bower.patrick@gmail.com



Introduction

As an accomplished product designer with a solid foundation in front-end development, I bring a wealth of expertise that bridges UX, design, and engineering. My approach integrates rapid prototyping in code and user testing to drive tangible outcomes. With exceptional leadership and communication abilities, I excel in cross-functional collaboration and adeptly navigate creative, technical, and business domains.

Skills	Tools
Product Design UX & Research Front-End Dev Leadership	Figma VS Code Adobe CC React
Experience	
Senior Product Designer, RAC (contracto Automotive services	June 2023 - Sep 2024 (1y 3m)
Design Leadership UX UI Prototypin	g Design System
Highlights include:	
 in a 1.5% increase in conversion rates. Designed over 50 innovative compone establishing and documenting best processes. Created and facilitated productive stal innovation, and delivered engaging prothroughout the project lifecycle. 	keholder workshops, promoting discovery and esentations to the broader business audience
Senior Product Designer, DAZN	Sep 2020 - May 2023 (2y 8m)
Subscription based global sports streaming pl	atform
Design Leadership UX UI Prototypin	g Coding Design System
Highlights include:	
 Employing high-fidelity interaction des processes and increase release cycles 	ign to expedite user testing and engineering by 10-20%.

• Self-initiated design tooling solutions for Figma and project data analysis.

across multiple streaming platforms for global audiences.

• Mentoring and educating across the business to improve the design process, enable cross-functional teams and establish a design system.

Owning end-to-end process for impactful features released using data-driven design

Experience cont.

Design Engineer, Buildit (Wipro Digital)

Mar 2018 - Sep 2020 (2y 6m)

Consultancy working with Fortune 500 companies in Healthcare • Banking • Energy • Insurance

Design Coding Leadership UX UI Prototyping Design System

Highlights include:

- · Leading design in creating new products for organisations such as Halifax Bank and CounterWeight (NHS).
- Facilitating workshops to align stakeholders, define complex processes and cocreate solutions for organisations such as Lloyds Bank, BP & GSK.
- Establishing a lean process framework to define a tailored cross-functional process and increase sales leads by up to 30%.
- Designing and implementing large-scale internal tools to enhance efficiency for organisations such as Aviva and Cynergy Bank.

Front End Engineer, Digital Detox (acquired by EY) Nov 2012 - Mar 2018 (5y 4m)

Development consultancy working in Healthcare • Enterprise • Banking • Telecommunications

Coding Leadership Prototyping

Highlights include:

- Developing experiences for millions of users across global applications.
- Co-developed Vodafone's Web Simplicity Design System Framework.
- Drive and consult on global adoption of WS Framework, including on-site delivery.
- Led product line definition and development for Bupa.
- Spearheaded engineering of multiple startup products, including Vala Health.

Design and Front-End Development, Contractor

Aug 2010 - Nov 2012 (2y 3m)

Contractor across various sectors including Retail • Publishing • Advertising • Fashion • Beauty

Design Coding Leadership UX UI

- · Worked with numerous clients, including Firebrand, Glock, UAL, ASOS, and FIFA, to craft tailored design and front-end development solutions.
- Delivered a diverse portfolio of projects ranging from custom print services to advanced e-commerce flows.
- Acted as a liaison between sales, marketing, and production teams to ensure successful project outcomes.

Designer, various agencies

Feb 2007 - Jul 2010 (3y 5m)

Full time for agencies across different sectors

Design

 Delivered creative design solutions for renowned clients, including BBC, Universal Music, AEG, Fenchurch working for boutique agencies.

Education

Birmingham UCE | 2:1 BA Visual Communication | 2001 - 2004